

JUSTIN ALFRED PAULSON

6729 E 86th Place Tulsa, OK 74133 (918) 949-5246 justinapaulson@gmail.com

Profile

I love to develop products from inception all the way through to production. I have experience in a number of different programming languages and team structures. I can manage a team or I can code as a member. I am very creative and have worked to build new products and services everywhere I have worked. My true passion lies in inventing and improving products, and in restructuring and developing internal tools and processes. I'm not the guy that just does his work and goes home; I'm the guy that consistently brings up ideas and finds new areas where I can have a positive impact. I'd love to hear what you are working on and how I can help.

Experience

Waterfield Energy, Tulsa, OK

www.waterfieldenergysoftware.com

Senior Developer and Team Lead, 2013-Present

- Created an on-boarding program that improved the amount of time needed for new developers to reach full
 productivity.
- Developed a web app to serve as a developer handbook with documentation, UI guides, links to educational materials, and programming style guides using Jekyll.
- Coded dozens of features including context-based search, a modal editing framework, and computational processes written in go.
- Created multiple single-page backbonejs applications including the front-end javascript and the server side ruby on rails code as a JSON API.
- Trained multiple developers using the on-boarding program I created.
- · Managed 6 remote developers in Costa Rica.
- Developed technical training courses for non-technical business staff.

AAON Inc, Tulsa, OK

www.aaon.com

Electrical Design Engineer, 2010-2013

- Implemented a modal master program for the controller which could be easily configured to operate hundreds of different HVAC configurations, including a function that could configure the program automatically.
- · Wrote custom NiagaraAX components in Java.
- Solitarily created an iOS application to interface controllers for access to setpoints, I/Os, alarms, network configuration, and histories.
- Created documentation for controls including an engineering catalog detailing and a user's manual describing multiple ways to interface the controller.
- Designed building management system to integrate controls of all the AAON factory HVAC equipment.
- Designed custom iOS application for CEO's home which integrated four HVAC units and a boiler loop into a simple to use interface.

EPM, Fulton, MO

www.epmctc.com

Software Engineer Level 3, 2008-2010

- · Trained and supervised engineering interns.
- Designed controls for many different types of heating and cooling units including freezers, boilers, and chillers.
- Traveled to sites to diagnose and correct problems with temperature controls.
- · Wrote controls on embedded systems using assembly code for microcontrollers.
- Created web-based graphical user interfaces for control computers using PHP and SQL databases.

University of Missouri, Columbia, MO

www.mizzou.edu

Undergraduate Research Technician Level II, 2007-2008

- · Maintained high safety standards for facility operation.
- Documented the photon absorption of SiC material using a number of lasers and photocells.
- Used Brewster's Angle to determine the refractive indices of the SiC material.

Goodrich Quality Theaters, Grand Rapids, MI

www.gqti.com

General Manager, Capital 8 and Capital 4 Theaters, Jefferson City, MO 2004-2006

- · Controlled costs on payroll, maintenance, and daily operations.
- · Achieved the largest commission bonus of any General Manager, based on cost and customer satisfaction.
- Improved the quality of the film presentations by over 80%.
- Staffed and Trained employees on theater operations and customer service interactions.
- Scheduled films with emphasis on payroll control and revenue expectations.

Education

University of Missouri, 2006-2008

Graduated with a B.S. in Computer Engineering, a B.S. in Electrical Engineering, and a minor in Philosophy. My senior project was the creation of wifi-enabled parking meters that can be monitored and paid for from either an iPhone application or a website.

University of Illinois-Urbana Champaign, 2002-2004

Studied philosophy and computer science.

Illinois Institute of Technology 2000-2002

Camras-NEXT scholarship Studied Computer Science and Electrical Engineering.

Skills

Ruby on Rails, Javascript, Coffeescript, Backbone.js, Meteor, Jekyll, Objective-C, iOS development, Java, NiagaraAX, BACnet, LonWorks, Modbus, Assembly, PHP, MySQL, markdown. I can quickly learn any language or code base and have excellent customer service skills both written and verbal.

Organizations

MENSA, IEEE, USATriathlon, Marathon Maniacs